<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Miscellaneous | Fuzzing the Web]]></title>
  <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/categories/miscellaneous/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-03T01:38:13+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://fuzzingtheweb.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Javi Manzano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back for Christmas- Turrón style]]></title>
    <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2014/01/03/back-for-christmas/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-03T01:22:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2014/01/03/back-for-christmas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m back here since this Monday morning, that&rsquo;s one of the few and vague reasons I haven&rsquo;t written in a few days. That and Christmas excitement. New year&rsquo;s eve has been brutal this year. I can&rsquo;t remember a night as epic as this year&rsquo;s has been, hard to believe. Specially because I don&rsquo;t usually enjoy new year&rsquo;s eve at all.</p>

<p>I brought the new camera to Spain and I&rsquo;ve some time to spend learning the basics about it. After reading some book introductions and blog posts, I&rsquo;ve got a common message from all of them: I should try to make tons of pictures. Apparently &ldquo;learning by doing&rdquo; is the best way of learning. Good stuff. I&rsquo;ve also started uploading some of them to <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jgasteiz/">my flickr account</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3822/11719225215_4f406bfc08_z.jpg" alt="vinyl" /></p>

<p>And that&rsquo;s all folks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another flat goes away]]></title>
    <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/12/12/another-flat-goes-away/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-12T18:06:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/12/12/another-flat-goes-away</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today will be the last night in my current flat, the place where I&rsquo;ve probably spent more time during the last 12 months. Sanctuary for watching films, playing games, lazing, sleeping and, sometimes, working.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2866/11342901484_931b7d029c_z.jpg" alt="My desk and bookshelf" /></p>

<p>On Saturday morning I will regret things like having a guitar or heavy books. Every time I&rsquo;ve bought something during the last year I&rsquo;ve thought for a while on the moving one day I would have to do and how much I would hate myself for that. It didn&rsquo;t make buy less.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7364/11342899124_b614ff504d_z.jpg" alt="Berlin is a bitch, and then you marry. Nice souvenir I bought in a shop in Kreuzberg" /></p>

<p>The good thing about this bookself is that it represents most of the things I&rsquo;ve done and places I&rsquo;ve visited during this year. It&rsquo;s not shown in the picture, but some Russian souvenirs live in the lowest shelf.</p>

<p><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7407/11342785855_f7b3f45506_z.jpg" alt="Books I've bought during this year" /></p>

<p>Kindles might be a perfect substitute for most of the books in the market, but I still believe there is nothing like paper when we talk about reference or programming books. Flipping pages >>> pressing buttons.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have time for writing more, there are a few bags that need to be filled with stuff. Wish me luck.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jobs - short review]]></title>
    <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/11/26/jobs-short-review/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T08:10:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/11/26/jobs-short-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://lh6.googleusercontent.com/zQvObkDlsk-J7_fDNZFw0qGRR69ngA0ggi0CEBl52_0=w519-h525-no" alt="Jobs, 2013" /></p>

<p>The film was ok, but</p>

<ul>
<li><p>did anyone else had the feeling that Steve Jobs (and Jonathan Ive) got extremely caricatured? They looked more like programmed machines to follow one or two behaviours than humans! I still can&rsquo;t understand how Wozniak could put up with him for more than half of the movie.</p></li>
<li><p>again, <em>Steve Jobs'</em> way of facing problems seemed so unhuman. It&rsquo;s well known he was a &ldquo;special&rdquo; guy for not being the nicest boss / father ever, but I would feel quite offended if anyone pictured me in a film like this. I&rsquo;d feel offended if he was my family or friend, I think.</p></li>
<li><p>have they put all Apple commercials together as a script for Jonathan Ive&rsquo;s role? They made him look like a weirdo. Once more, I&rsquo;d feel offended if I was him.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Apart from this, the film was fine. Entertaining, although I&rsquo;d say it&rsquo;s not worthy paying much for watching it :/</p>

<p>I give it two thirds of a star out of two stars. Because weird roles deserve weird ratings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Young, qualified and jobless]]></title>
    <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/07/01/young-qualified-and-jobless/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-01T23:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/07/01/young-qualified-and-jobless</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jul/01/jobless-europe-young-qualified">this article</a> in my way back home, which was in the home page of <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/">The Guardian UK</a>. Sad feelings, sad stories. Close and familiar.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have many friends that have left Spain because of the crisis. I&rsquo;m actually the only one who has done that in my group of friends of Vitoria (my hometown). And the crisis wasn&rsquo;t my main reason for leaving, to be honest, but that&rsquo;s a story for another post. But yeah, I can see many of <em>us</em> walking everyday through the streets of London, talking Spanish to each other, some of them going back home after work, others carrying CVs from one place to another.</p>

<p>Sometimes, when I hear a conversation in Spanish in the tube I usually turn off my music and pay attention. Back in Spain, that would be being gossip, but I don&rsquo;t have that feeling here.</p>

<p>The other day for instance, I was listening to a couple of guys talking in the tube. For their accent, I&rsquo;d say they were from Madrid. One of them was apparently doing quite good. He was happy with his salary and he could even save money, something very uncommon between the spaniard community here, taking into account that most of us work as waiters, kitchen porters and other positions that don&rsquo;t require special qualification. But the other one wasn&rsquo;t that happy. I couldn&rsquo;t get what his job was, but he wasn&rsquo;t happy with it at all. He sounded a bit desperate and nervous. Anyway, I don&rsquo;t want to guess.</p>

<p>Is it always the fault of the politicians? Well, I agree the ones we have in Spain are in their majority shameless idiots. But I think it&rsquo;s most a matter of none knowing how to fix this.</p>

<p>I remember a conversation I had in my last year of high school with a friend. We were rambling about how the future would be, regarding employment (an advanced topic for a high school conversation maybe? :/ ). What both of us were wondering was how different would be the future employment, after so many technological advances. And we knew nothing, back then in 2007, because since then this has gone way further. Basically, the question we were asking ourselves was: <em>Does the world really need so many working people?</em></p>

<p>Back then, both of us thought that if the unemployment was so high is basically because there are no jobs for everyone, plain and simple. Stuff like travel agencies, estate agencies (in Spain, probably the 70% of them are gone), music stores, media stores, cinemas, post offices&hellip; all of them seem from a past age. And many more to come.</p>

<p>What we used to say, without giving proper arguments, is that the human race is getting to a point in which we shouldn&rsquo;t work that much. But the established economy model isn&rsquo;t prepared for that yet. I&rsquo;m sure we&rsquo;ll see some kind of global economy reorganization within ten years. I would like to see it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBQ time]]></title>
    <link href="http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/06/24/bbq-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T23:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://fuzzingtheweb.com/blog/2013/06/24/bbq-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few pics from this weekend, which I&rsquo;ve shortly spent in my hometown, Vitoria-Gasteiz :)</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-MlGTXhLHNeU/UcYywAjlQkI/AAAAAAAAJMw/CrSIwA601oQ/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_141757.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-MrW2w4g6Be8/UcYyzhosf_I/AAAAAAAAJNE/RslMXI7hWFA/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_143307.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-rklv1ENL-hI/UcYy2HeumYI/AAAAAAAAJNQ/CyO0NwvLfSw/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_143327.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-T2ErON2mKzY/UcYy64p0s7I/AAAAAAAAJNo/c1N6TfHBn_c/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_143334.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-gLQy5-HoC0I/Ucfgwe51ivI/AAAAAAAAJSc/Sgy4tqWJATk/w479-h800-no/2013-06-23" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jIBRTU10QvQ/UcYzGjcmjYI/AAAAAAAAJOQ/RTA_sy3eFpo/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_164841.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-GXNDdu5P5sU/UcfguuZeESI/AAAAAAAAJSU/iUWM7Etwod4/w800-h600-no/2013-06-23" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-kmwh1YX8Hag/UcfgxocBfiI/AAAAAAAAJSk/Y4ahG5VBsHw/w800-h600-no/2013-06-23" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bzIW4WH4t4A/UcYzLzacbuI/AAAAAAAAJOo/J0BV76gXwUs/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_164855.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s always a pleasure and a bit sad going back to Vitoria for a few days. One part of me, wants to stay there. Another part wants to come back. But I always manage to get moments like these, lucky me!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
