<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Miscellaneous | Fuzzing the Web]]></title>
  <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/categories/miscellaneous/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-21T20:59:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jgasteiz.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Javi Manzano]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Young, qualified and jobless]]></title>
    <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/07/01/young-qualified-and-jobless/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-01T23:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/07/01/young-qualified-and-jobless</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve read <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/jul/01/jobless-europe-young-qualified">this article</a> in my way back home, which was in the home page of <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/">The Guardian UK</a>. Sad feelings, sad stories. Close and familiar.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have many friends that have left Spain because of the crisis. I&rsquo;m actually the only one who has done that in my group of friends of Vitoria (my hometown). And the crisis wasn&rsquo;t my main reason for leaving, to be honest, but that&rsquo;s a story for another post. But yeah, I can see many of <em>us</em> walking everyday through the streets of London, talking Spanish to each other, some of them going back home after work, others carrying CVs from one place to another.</p>

<p>Sometimes, when I hear a conversation in Spanish in the tube I usually turn off my music and pay attention. Back in Spain, that would be being gossip, but I don&rsquo;t have that feeling here.</p>

<p>The other day for instance, I was listening to a couple of guys talking in the tube. For their accent, I&rsquo;d say they were from Madrid. One of them was apparently doing quite good. He was happy with his salary and he could even save money, something very uncommon between the spaniard community here, taking into account that most of us work as waiters, kitchen porters and other positions that don&rsquo;t require special qualification. But the other one wasn&rsquo;t that happy. I couldn&rsquo;t get what his job was, but he wasn&rsquo;t happy with it at all. He sounded a bit desperate and nervous. Anyway, I don&rsquo;t want to guess.</p>

<p>Is it always the fault of the politicians? Well, I agree the ones we have in Spain are in their majority shameless idiots. But I think it&rsquo;s most a matter of none knowing how to fix this.</p>

<p>I remember a conversation I had in my last year of high school with a friend. We were rambling about how the future would be, regarding employment (an advanced topic for a high school conversation maybe? :/ ). What both of us were wondering was how different would be the future employment, after so many technological advances. And we knew nothing, back then in 2007, because since then this has gone way further. Basically, the question we were asking ourselves was: <em>Does the world really need so many working people?</em></p>

<p>Back then, both of us thought that if the unemployment was so high is basically because there are no jobs for everyone, plain and simple. Stuff like travel agencies, estate agencies (in Spain, probably the 70% of them are gone), music stores, media stores, cinemas, post offices&hellip; all of them seem from a past age. And many more to come.</p>

<p>What we used to say, without giving proper arguments, is that the human race is getting to a point in which we shouldn&rsquo;t work that much. But the established economy model isn&rsquo;t prepared for that yet. I&rsquo;m sure we&rsquo;ll see some kind of global economy reorganization within ten years. I would like to see it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BBQ time]]></title>
    <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/06/24/bbq-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-24T23:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/06/24/bbq-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few pics from this weekend, which I&rsquo;ve shortly spent in my hometown, Vitoria-Gasteiz :)</p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-MlGTXhLHNeU/UcYywAjlQkI/AAAAAAAAJMw/CrSIwA601oQ/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_141757.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-MrW2w4g6Be8/UcYyzhosf_I/AAAAAAAAJNE/RslMXI7hWFA/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_143307.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-rklv1ENL-hI/UcYy2HeumYI/AAAAAAAAJNQ/CyO0NwvLfSw/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_143327.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-T2ErON2mKzY/UcYy64p0s7I/AAAAAAAAJNo/c1N6TfHBn_c/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_143334.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-gLQy5-HoC0I/Ucfgwe51ivI/AAAAAAAAJSc/Sgy4tqWJATk/w479-h800-no/2013-06-23" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jIBRTU10QvQ/UcYzGjcmjYI/AAAAAAAAJOQ/RTA_sy3eFpo/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_164841.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-GXNDdu5P5sU/UcfguuZeESI/AAAAAAAAJSU/iUWM7Etwod4/w800-h600-no/2013-06-23" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-kmwh1YX8Hag/UcfgxocBfiI/AAAAAAAAJSk/Y4ahG5VBsHw/w800-h600-no/2013-06-23" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bzIW4WH4t4A/UcYzLzacbuI/AAAAAAAAJOo/J0BV76gXwUs/w1119-h839-no/IMG_20130622_164855.jpg" alt="bbq ullibarri" /></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s always a pleasure and a bit sad going back to Vitoria for a few days. One part of me, wants to stay there. Another part wants to come back. But I always manage to get moments like these, lucky me!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You should blog even if you have no readers]]></title>
    <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/04/17/you-should-blog-even-if-you-have-no-readers/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-17T23:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/04/17/you-should-blog-even-if-you-have-no-readers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read this post a couple of days ago and I have to say I concur in most of the points with the writer. Most of the reasons he talks about are the reasons why I blog. Not to make myself advertisement (at all), or because I have nothing better to do. Actually, most of the last posts I&rsquo;ve written are quite short because I have plenty of better things to do. For me is as recreational as reading a good book.</p>

<p>But yeah, as <em>Nathan Marz</em> says,  you should blog because it&rsquo;s good for you. You have very little to loose and a lot to win, such as intelligence! Well, not really, but it does help a lot making you think before talking and in a more organised way, in general.</p>

<p>And for me, that was only when I used to write in spanish. Now I&rsquo;m even practising english! Very little to loose, indeed.</p>

<p><a href="http://nathanmarz.com/blog/you-should-blog-even-if-you-have-no-readers.html">You should blog even if you have no readers &ndash; Nathan Marz</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RAF Museum]]></title>
    <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/raf-museum/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-15T23:48:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/04/15/raf-museum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a <em>museums</em> weekend and for the first time in months, we&rsquo;ve had warm weather in London. Since yesterday. I might recover part of my natural tan before August!</p>

<p>And I also haven&rsquo;t touch a keyboard during the weekend, which is cool. It&rsquo;s been some kind of disconnection weekend, something I&rsquo;m enjoying quite a lot lately. Anyway, I will probably compensate touching too much keyboard during this whole week, as usual.</p>

<p><img src="http://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-_pcmbWoxsk8/UWrLOH6ldpI/AAAAAAAAGug/bEseDeQMqew/s1041/IMG_20130414_134941.jpg" alt="RAF Museum 1" /></p>

<p><img src="http://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-dCmkTamyXYo/UWrLknhGg5I/AAAAAAAAGu4/Sy_ZvoDXm4g/s1041/IMG_20130414_135018.jpg" alt="RAF Museum 2" /></p>

<p><img src="http://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-YY34hR19Z50/UWrMD-OxenI/AAAAAAAAGvc/KOTcF_UAhAI/s1041/IMG_20130414_135630.jpg" alt="RAF Museum 3" /></p>

<p><img src="http://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-R-ZwMx4gRIw/UWrMPlDZ8qI/AAAAAAAAGvo/pNudU5BLINk/s1041/IMG_20130414_135643.jpg" alt="RAF Museum 4" /></p>

<p><img src="http://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-1h898xXJM6Y/UWrPXmQBZuI/AAAAAAAAGyc/GhIKtYFx_XY/s1041/IMG_20130414_145342.jpg" alt="RAF Museum 5" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nomad]]></title>
    <link href="http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/01/06/nomad/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T23:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jgasteiz.github.io/blog/2013/01/06/nomad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8364/8342367280_e2edb34945_o.png" title="nomad" alt="Nomadic Pursuits Cover" /></p>

<p>This picture is part of Yawning Man&rsquo;s last album cover, <a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-x3gv-U9deWI/Tj8d8wR8VOI/AAAAAAAABFk/xihwaQHkCdI/s1600/Yawning%2BMan%2B-%2B2010%2B-%2BNomadic%2BPursuits.jpg" title="nomadic pursuits">Nomadic Pursuits</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Nomadic life</strong></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been almost six years since I started living away from home and I&rsquo;ve had the feeling of not belonging anywhere for all of these years. I&rsquo;ve lived in seven or eight different places since then and I spend only a few weeks per year in Vitoria. I guess I don&rsquo;t want to belong anywhere. Someone could tell I am looking for something, moving this much, I don&rsquo;t know. I&rsquo;ll figure it out someday.</p>

<p><strong>Desert</strong></p>

<p>Furthermore, it&rsquo;s also related to the desert. The desert rock is the music genre Yawning Man invented back in the eighties-nineties. In terms of <em>desert</em>, it could describe most of the stuff I&rsquo;ve had in my mind these last years: how I&rsquo;ve behaved and felt with myself and most of the times with other people. The desert could be very warm during the day but it gets really cold at night. That&rsquo;s a close description of how I&rsquo;ve been since I moved away from home. And somehow, the desert reminds loneliness too.</p>

<p><strong>Why now?</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://sp6.fotolog.com/photo/6/12/46/javitheskater/1212073336_f.jpg" title="ah">The first tattoo I&rsquo;ve ever thought about</a> was six years ago, during my first months at university. I had the design completely worked out, but I never took a step forward and actually did it. And it&rsquo;s something I regret now. That one meant my adolescence, those amazing years in Vitoria with all my friends, partying and playing music. After moving to London, I knew I was closing another stage in my life and it felt like the right time for doing this.</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>This picture completely describes the last and closer stage in my life. I couldn&rsquo;t be comfortable with something which will try to describe the present or even the future. This is what it has been, not what it is or it will be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
